# **ALEKSA TEŠIĆ**

**③** <u>imafikus.com</u> ☑ aleksatesicteske@gmail.com **〔** (+381) 60 424 37 69 **⑤** <u>github.com/Imafikus</u> **in** <u>Aleksa Tešić</u>

# **ABOUT**

Software engineer experienced in designing, building and maintaining systems from the ground up. I've worked on every part of the stack, from bare metal deployments to frontend frameworks.

I love working on meaningful products and tools, both internal and external. Interacting with users and designing useful features that people are actually going to use is what keeps me motivated at work.

My side project, Notify Me, has been running for 4 years now and has more than 7000 customers.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Software Engineer - Microsoft (April 2024 - present)

- Managing teams' SDK integrations for different internal teams (Excel, Al Hub, Outlook...), ensuring that timelines and best practices are met
- Worked on optimizing CI/CD pipelines. Reduced total pipeline run time by 10% and reduced compute time used by 20%
- Added visual coherence features that enabled our partner teams to quickly switch to the new UI
- Created and and subsequently improved onboarding guide for the new-comers in the team reducing onboarding time from 2 weeks to 1 day

#### Co-Founder - Notify Me (October 2018 - present)

- Built and launched website monitoring SaaS product serving 7,000+ users with 3k monthly visitors
- Developed full-stack application including payment system integration from scratch
- Migrated infrastructure from GCP to self-managed Kubernetes cluster on Hetzner with < 1h downtime
- Architected microservice-based system using MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Prometheus and Grafana
- Achieved 2-minute deployment pipeline from commit to production
- Handling everything from engineering to sales and customer support
- These days I'm focused (almost) only on the product side of things
- Currently working on this product with 2 of my friends in our spare time

#### Board Member at Petnica Science Center (September 2023 - present)

- Leading STEM department and serving on PSC board (volunteer position)
- Responsible for department budgeting, scheduling, and curriculum development
- Managing team of 30 assistants across 3 different courses, organizing lectures and workshops for high school students
- Organizing annual <u>web3 camp</u> for students. Mainly focused on social media presence and finding sponsors for the camp
- · Contributing to strategic planning and stakeholder negotiations with sponsors and government officials
- This is a volunteer position that I do in my spare time.

#### SRE & Software Engineer - Tenderly (March 2022 - November 2023)

- Led internal tooling development and CI/CD infrastructure for entire company
- Designed and extended custom configuration system for the complete backend codebase
- Built and maintained in-house CLI tool that enabled 10-minute deployment pipeline from commit to production
- Scaled CI/CD pipeline to support 3 Kubernetes clusters and 2x size increase in engineering head count
- Developed microservices that caught regressions on main backend data pipeline which was, at the time, part of the critical company infrastructure

### Devops Engineer - Connect the Dots (September 2021 - March 2022)

- Led migration from Docker to Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) infrastructure
- Implemented distributed tracing across complete backend repo to optimize performance and find bottlenecks
- Developed and enhanced CI/CD pipelines using GitHub Actions
- Managed Infrastructure as Code (IaC) deployments with Terraform

# Junior Devops Engineer - <u>Itekako</u> (September 2020 – June 2021)

- Deployed and managed bare metal infrastructure using Ansible and Vagrant for multiple clients
- Implemented automated CI/CD pipelines and monitoring solutions for client applications
- Developed automation scripts using Bash and Python to streamline operations
- Provided technical support and infrastructure guidance to development teams

# Junior Backend Engineer - Penta (now Qonto) (March 2019 - August 2020)

- Implemented CRUD endpoints and integrated third-party service APIs
- Led migration from ES5 to ES6 TypeScript codebase
- Decomposed monolithic architecture into microservices
- Developed and maintained backend infrastructure

#### **EDUCATION**